[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家早上好
Thank you so much for coming to
非常感谢大家能够
our session.
参加开发者大会
My name is Sara Radi.
我叫 Sara Radi
I'm a software engineer in the
是 Apple 本地化团队的一名
Localization Team at Apple and
软件工程师
today we'll be joined by my
今天我会和我的同事
colleagues, Vivian and Chris, to
Vivian 和 Chris 一起
talk about new location
来谈谈使用 Xcode 10 以后的
workflows with Xcode 10.
新的本地化工作流程
So first I would like to start
首先我想跟大家一起
with a quick overview of how the
快速回顾下
localization process used to
在 Xcode 10 之前的
work before Xcode 10.
本地化工作流程
Then I will introduce the Xcode
然后我会介绍 Xcode 本地化目录
Localization Catalog, which is
这将是一个全新的模板
the new format for exports and
用于在 Xcode 10 上
imports in your localizations in
导入和导出
Xcode 10.
你的本地化文件
Finally, Chris will talk about
最后 Chris 将讨论
how to localize Siri Shortcuts
如何使用目标定义文件
by using an Intent definition
来本地化 Siri 捷径
file which is a new file format
该文件也是我们今年
we introduced this year as well
在 Xcode 10 中引入的
in Xcode 10.
一种新的文件格式
So let's get started with a
让我们开始快速
quick overview.
概述一下
So before Xcode 10, if you had a
在 Xcode 10 之前
project that contains
如果你有一个包含
localizations that your
App 支持的
application supports, we look
本地化的项目
for strings base localizable
我们将在项目中查找
resources in your project.
字符基串的本地化资源
So these strings can be defined
这些字符串可以在源代码
in your source code, your
故事板文件
storyboard files, your strings
字符串文件
files, or your strings
或字符串字典中定义
So once we identify these
我们识别了这些资源后
resources, we extract strings
我们就从中
from them and we export them in
提取字符串
an XLIFF format.
并以 XLIFF 格式导出它们
So XLIFF is an industry standard
XLIFF 是一个行业标准
and most localizers are already
大多数本地化从业者
familiar with.
都已经非常熟悉了
So that's what you will be
这些就是你要
sending over for translations.
发出去翻译的
So once you get your XLIFF files
在你的 XLIFF 文件
back translated on imports, we
翻译完成后 作为导入文件
add them to localizable
我们将它们添加到
resources in your Xcode projects
你的 Xcode 项目的
with the new translations that
可本地化资源中
are provided in the XLIFF files.
其中包含 XLIFF 文件中的新翻译
So that is pretty
这个流程现在变得非常简单
Now, the XLIFF format provides a
XLIFF 格式
lot of benefits for you as a
为开发者提供了极大的好处
First, it helps you to extract
首先它可以帮助你
the localization work from your
将本地化工作从代码中抽离出来
code so you don't have to make
这样就不必在源代码中
any language assumptions in your
进行任何的语言假设
XLIFF files also holds the
XLIFF 文件同时保留了
content to be localized from
开发者语言和
your development language along
翻译本地化的内容
with the translations so your
以便本地化人员
translators can do their work
可以在你提供的
right in the XLIFF files that
XLIFF 文件中
you have provided.
直接翻译
In addition to that, instead of
除此之外 XLIFF
handing over multiple file types
是一个非常好的工具
and keep track of them, XLIFF is
它将来自不同资源
a really nice tool that
和不同文件类型的字符串
consolidates strings from
合并到一个文档中
different resources and
而不是交付
different file types into one
多个文件类型
single document.
并对其进行记录
But what XLIFF does not provide
但是 XLIFF 没有
your localizers, it does not
为本地化人员提供
give them that visual and
视觉环境和
functional context.
功能性的上下文
It does not provide the resource
它不提供资源数据
data like assets in your
比如项目中的素材
For example, a storyboard file
例如故事板文件
will be very helpful for your
将非常有助于
localizers to picture how your
本地化人员
UI is laid out in your
想象你的 UI 在
development language.
开发语言中的布局
It also does not provide with
它也不提供关于
the custom metadata about the
XLIFF 的自定义元数据
And finally, the XLIFF we
最后 我们现在生成的
generate today does not have
XLIFF 文件没有大小
size and length restrictions
和长度属性的限制
attributes and that might be
而知晓限制对本地化人员
very helpful for your localizers
大有好处
to know if a given string will
如果给定的字符串显示
be showing on a Watch screen or
在 Watch/iPhone/iPad 屏幕上
an iPhone screen or an iPad
本地化人员会
screen to make decisions about
自主选择翻译的长度
So why is context important for
为什么上下文
your localizers?
对你的本地化人员而言十分重要呢
So if we take a look at this
如果我们来看下
example from a travel app that
之后要给大家演示的
we will be showing you later in
一个旅游 App 的例子
our demo, so if you look at the
如果你看到导航栏
string that says "Book" on the
右边的 “Book” 按钮
right corner of the Navigation
我们这些
bar, it's kind of clear to all
坐在房间里的人
of us here in the room that
都十分清楚
"book" refers to something
“book” 指的是某些
related to travels because we
和旅行相关的东西
have that visual context right
因为我们面前有
in front of us that says start
相应的视觉环境
day and dates, number of
时间 日期
travelers and the price.
游客数目和价格
But if you send your translators
但是如果你给你的本地化人员
an XLIFF files, the only thing
发送一个 XLIFF 文件
they see there is just the
他们唯一看到的
string "Book" and that don't
就是字符串 “Book”
have that visual context that we
没有我们之前看到
were looking at earlier.
视觉上下文
So Book can refer to two
所以 “Book” 可以指
different things.
两个完全不同的东西
It can be a noun in the context
它可以是名词 指读书的书
of reading a book or it can be a
也可以是动词
verb in the context of booking a
指预定酒店房间
hotel room somewhere or a flight
机票或旅行的这个动作
I actually asked our Russian
我问我们的俄语翻译
translator if he can translate
他是否能帮我翻译
the word "book" for me without
“Book” 这个词
giving him any additional
没有任何额外的上下文
context and he came up with all
他想出了所有
these different options.
这些不同的选择
So without giving him that extra
因此如果不给他
context, it would be very
提供额外的上下文
difficult for him to decide
他将很难决定在
which string to show in the UI
UI 中为俄罗斯用户
for Russian users, for example.
显示哪个义项
Context can also be important
上下文对于
for your localizers to decide
本地化人员来讲
about the length of the
在决定所使用的翻译长度时也十分重要
So if we take a look at this
我们来看一下这个例子
example, so I have this phrase
这有一个短语
that says, "Booking confirmed"
“预订确认”
in English and it fits just fine
用英文显示在
on a Watch screen, but in
Watch 屏幕上就很合适
French, for example, it
但是在法语中却是截断的
So first of all, when it
首先 截断了
truncates, it doesn't look that
在 UI 中看起来
nice in the UI and sometimes the
不是很妥当
truncation can change the
有时候截断甚至会
meaning of the word.
改变单词的意思
It can even be offensive for
甚至会冒犯你的用户
It can be like funny, like in
它可以很有趣
this example, like the phase
就像在这个例子中
does not say that your booking
它的意思根本不是
was confirmed anymore.
你的预订已经被确认
It says our booking was stupid
而是说这个预订很蠢 完全不是我想要的字样
So we see that context is very
因此我们认为
important to provide to your
为了向客户或本地化人员
customers or to your localizers
带来高质量的
to ship high-quality
本地化内容
localization.
提供上下文非常重要
So now I would like to introduce
现在我想介绍一下
the Xcode Localization Catalog,
Xcode 本地化目录
which is the new format for
这是一种在 Xcode 10 中
exporting and importing your
导入和导出
localizations in Xcode 10.
本地化内容的新格式
So what is an Xcode Localization
什么是 Xcode 本地化目录
It is a new type of localization
它是一种具有
artifact that has that .xcloc
.xcloc 扩展的新型本地化工具
It is produced by the export
由 Xcode 中的
localization command in Xcode,
导出本地化命令生成
so it's the same command that
和 XLIFF 文件
used to export XLIFF files
在 Xcode 10 之前的
before Xcode 10.
导出命令相同
And it is consumed by the import
和导入本地化
localization command.
命令合并
And the main thing about the
本地化目录主要是
Localization Catalog is that it
支持所有
supports all of your localizable
可本地化的素材
assets, which means anything
这意味着在
that you mark as localizable in
Xcode 项目中
Xcode projects, it will be
所有可本地化的素材
supported by Localization
本地化目录都支持
Catalog and that is beyond
不仅仅是
strings files.
字符串文件
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Another important thing about
本地化目录的
the Localization Catalog is that
另一个重要特性
it provides that additional
是它为本地化者
contextual information for your
提供了附加的
localizers.
上下文信息
So we built the Xcode
我们在 XLIFF 格式之上
the XLIFF format.
构建了 Xcode 本地化目录
So if we take a look at our
我们来看一下
example earlier, so all of our
先前的的示例
strings base localizable
那么我们所有的字符串
resources will be extracted in
基本可本地化资源
an XLIFF format and anything
都将以 XLIFF 格式提取
else that you have marked as
并且你在项目中标记为
localizable in your project will
可本地化的任何其他内容
be supported by the Localization
都受本地化目录支持
Catalog and exported in an xcloc
并以 xcloc 形式 以及包含
along with the XLIFF files that
字符串的 XLIFF 文件
contains the strings.
的形式导出
So let's take a look closely at
我们来仔细看看
what is inside a Localization
本地化目录里面的内容
So inside your xcloc, you will
在你的 xcloc 中
find a contents.json file, which
可以找到一个 contents.json 文件
contains metadata about the
其中包含有关导出的
exported Localization Catalog.
本地化目录的元数据
So it has information like the
里面有诸如
development language of your
App 开发语言的信息
application, the target language
导出的本地化
of the exported Localization
目录的目标语言信息
It has information about the
还有有关生成该
tool that generated that
本地化目录的
Localization Catalog.
工具的信息
In this case, it's Xcode, so you
在这种情况下
will find information like the
它就是 Xcode
version number and the build
你可以找到 Xcode 的
number of Xcode.
版本号和构建版本号等信息
And finally, it has the version
它还有导出的
number of the exported
本地化目录的版本号
Next inside the generated xcloc,
接下来在生成的 xcloc 中
you will find Localized Contents
你会看到本地化内容目录
And Localized Contents contains
本地化内容包含
all of your localizable
项目中所有
resources in the project and
可本地化的资源
this is the main directory where
这是本地化人员
your localizers will be doing
工作的主要目录
So inside Localized Contents, as
因此正如我所提到的那样
I mentioned, you will find an
在本地化内容中
XLIFF document that has all the
你会看到一个 XLIFF 文档
project localized strings as
其中包含所有项目本地化字符串
well as non-strings localizable
以及可本地化的非字符串
assets like images, for example,
素材（如图像）
if you want to localize those.
如果你想要本地化这些内容
So those assets will be
这些素材将与
organized into the same file
本地化目录中的 Xcode 项目
system hierarchy as your Xcode
归进相同的
projects inside the Localization
文件系统层次结构中
And your localizers can also use
你的本地化人员
Localized Content to override
还可以使用本地化内容
any resources specifically for
来覆盖针对某种语言
the language like interface
的任何资源
builder files, for example.
例如界面构建文件
Next, inside the Localization
接下来 在本地化目录中
Catalog, we generate a Source
我们生成一个源内容目录
Contents directory and this is
这主要是为
mainly provided for context.
上下文提供的
So Source Contents contains
源内容包含用于
assets that were used to produce
生成本地化内容的素材
the Localized Contents like
用故事板举个例子
storyboards for example that
会有助于本地化人员
will be helpful for your
了解到你的用户界面
laid out in your development
是如何布置在
language so they can make
开发语言中的
decisions about the length of
以便决定
the translations.
翻译的长度
So even if your localized
即使你的
strings are coming from your
本地化字符串来自源代码
your source code inside the
我们也不会在源内容中
Source Contents.
生成你的源代码
So those assets that are mainly
主要为上下文提供的素材
also organized into the same
也将被归入相同的
file system hierarchy are your
文件系统层次结构中
Xcode project inside the
即你的本地化目录
Localization Catalog and, as I
中的 Xcode 项目
mentioned, this is mainly
正如我所提到的
provided for context even if
这主要是为上下文提供的
your localizers go and change
即使你的本地化人员
your source context on import,
在导入中更改你的源上下文
Xcode will just ignore them and
Xcode 也会忽略它们
will not import these resources
不会将这些资源导回
back into your projects.
到你的项目中
Finally, inside your
最后在本地化目录中
Localization Catalog, you will
你将找到一个 Notes 目录
find a Notes directory and this
这主要是为
is mainly provided for you to
本地化人员
give any additional contextual
提供任何附加的
information for your localizers.
上下文信息
That can be screenshots data
比如说 它可以是
from your UI Attachments for
来自 UI 附件的
example.
屏幕快照数据
It can be a Readme file or a
可以是自述文件或电影
movie that explains information
解释有关你的 App
about your app or anything
的信息或任何你认为
really you think that will be
对本地化人员
important for your localizers.
非常重要的信息
So that was the Xcode
这就是 Xcode
Localization Catalog structure.
本地化目录结构
And we have been also working on
我们也一直
updating the Xcode build command
致力于更新 Xcode
line tools.
构建命令行工具
So now on exports, we generate
现在在导出中
an Xcode Localization Catalog.
我们生成一个 Xcode 本地化目录
And on imports, the imports
在导入时
command is backwards compatible.
导入命令向后兼容
So if you still have those old
如果你仍使用
XLIFF files, you can still
旧的 XLIFF 文件
important them back into your
仍然可以将它们重新导入你的项目中
project or you can import back
或者你可以导入
the new Localization Catalog.
新的本地化目录
And with that, I would like to
就是这样
hand it over to Vivian to give
下面请 Vivian
you a demonstration about the
给大家演示一下
Localization Catalog.
本地化目录
Thank you so much.
非常感谢 [ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Sara.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Sara
Alright, so we've been working
是这样 我们一直在研究
on a travel app and what makes
一个旅行 App
this special is it's the first
这个 App 的特别之处在于
app to let you plan vacations to
它是第一个让你计划到
other planets.
其他星球度假的 App
So we call it Vacation Planet.
所以我们称之为度假行星
Let's take a look.
我们来看一下 在启动画面上
we have this lovely logo with
有这个可爱的标志
the name of our app.
还有 App 的名称
And I'm just going to click
点按这里 打开浏览
Alright, so we can book a
我们可以预定航班
flight, an expedition, a cruise,
预定探险和巡航
or an entire vacation package.
或者整个假期
Let's go to Mars.
咱们去火星吧
Okay, now I need to choose where
现在我需要选择
on Mars to go and I think we
到火星上的哪个地方去
should check in on the NASA
我觉得可以试一试
Curiosity Rover.
NASA 好奇号漫游者
So let's go to Gale Creator.
那就去 Gale Creator 吧
We should definitely go after
肯定得在会议之后去
And let's go for a month.
我们去一个月吧
It's a really fast spaceship.
乘坐一艘非常快的宇宙飞船
I'm going to take Sara and Chris
我要带 Sara 和 Chris 一起去
with me, so three travelers.
所以一共是三个旅行者
That's a really cheap trip to
总之会是一次非常便宜的火星之旅
Alright, here's that Book button
这是大家之前看到的
you saw earlier.
那个 “Book” 按钮
And great, our booking is
很好 我们的预订已经确认
Now, of course, there's people
当然 地球上想要
all over Earth who would love to
去访问火星的人
visit Mars and they don't all
有些人的 iOS
use their iOS devices in
设备语言不是英文
So we're going to need to
所以我们需要
localize the app.
本地化这个 App
Let's go into Xcode and do that.
我们进入 Xcode
Alright, so I just need to
我只需要
select my project here.
选择我的项目
And under Info, under
在 Info 下面
Localizations, click Plus, and
本地化 点按加号
we're going to add French for
我们首先添加法语来试试看
Okay. So my storyboards are
我的故事板默认是
localizable by default, so
可本地化的
they're already checked.
所以它们已经被选中了
And a have a localizable
有一个可本地化的
stringsdict that I also already
字符串词典
marked localizable.
我也标记了可本地化
So I just need to click Finish.
我只需要点按完成（Finish）
Alright, at this point, Xcode
这时 Xcode 已经在
has created the fr.lproj in my
我的项目中创建了 fr.lproj
project and for by storyboards
并且通过故事板创建了
has created strings files with
带有我的英文字符串
copies of my English strings.
拷贝的字符串文件
So also copy my image because I
还拷贝了我的图像
have not marked it localizable.
因为我没有标记它可本地化
So let's do that.
所以需要我们来选择在右边 点按本地化（Localize）
There's no content shared
这个文件中的语言
between the languages in this
之间没有内容共享
So I need to put it in English
所以我需要把它变成英语
because that's my development
因为那是我默认的开发语言
Click Localize and check French
点按本地化（Localize）并勾选法语
to make that copy.
制作副本
Alright, there it is.
好了就是这样
Okay, now I'm ready to export
现在我准备
for localization.
导出本地化
I'll just select my project, go
我选择我的项目
to Editor, Export for
到编辑器
Localization.
导出本地化
Alright, I'm going to call this
把它命名为
vacationplanetloc, so I don't
vacationplanetloc
have to type out localization,
就不用打出本地化几个字了
and double check that I'm
然后连按我要
exporting for French and click
导出的法语 并点按存储（Save）
So now Xcode generates that
现在 Xcode 为我生成了
Xcode Localization Catalog for
Xcode 本地化目录
me and we can go into Finder and
可以在访达中查看
Alright, here we go.
好的那我们开始吧
Here is my French Xcode
这是我的法语 Xcode
Localization Catalog with that
本地化目录
.xcloc extension.
扩展名为 .xcloc
And inside, as Sara said,
就像 Sara 说的那样
there's the contents.json with
有我的 Xcode
metadata about my Xcode
本地化目录
Localization Catalog.
的元数据 contents.json
Next, we have Localized
接下来是本地化内容
So in here, I have an XLIFF, the
在这里有一个 XLIFF
same as if I had used Xcode 9.
和 Xcode 9 一样
You can see here it has all of
你可以看到这里有
my strings and here we can see
我所有的字符串
highlighted in red the
在这里我们可以看到
untranslated copies of the
红色突出显示未翻译的英文副本
And also in Localized Contents
和我的项目文件层次结构类似的
my project, I have that logo
本地化内容中有图标图像
So next let's look at Source
接下来我们来看源内容
This likewise mimics the file
同样仿照
hierarchy of my Xcode project.
Xcode 项目的文件层次结构
So I have my storyboards that
底层有故事板文件
are in base and I have the
还有信息 plist
English for my info plist
字符串的英文
strings, my localizable.strings
代码中定义的字符串的
for the strings defined in code,
localizable.strings
my localizable stringsdict and
可本地化的字符串字典和
the English version of the
图像的英文版本
So the last part of Xcode
所以 Xcode 本地化目录的
Localization Catalog is the
最后一部分是
Notes folder.
Notes 文件夹
And Xcode doesn't put anything
Xcode 不会在这里
in here, but yesterday, I ran my
放置任何东西
XCUI tests, which are a really
但昨天我运行了 XCUI 测试
easy way to create screenshots.
这是一个非常简单的创建屏幕快照的方法
And all my screenshots are saved
所有的屏幕快照都保存为
as attachments to my test.
测试的附件
So we can go back and look at my
所以我们可以回头看看
test results, see them.
测试结果
So for instance, I have my
例如我在这里添加了
splash screen added as an
启动画面
attachment here.
作为附件
There we go.
就是这样
Alright, so I'm just going to
在访达中
pull these up in Finder and copy
把它们拷贝到
them into the Notes folder.
Notes 文件夹中
So select Show in Finder.
选择在访达中显示（Show in Finder）
Alright, Show Package Contents,
显示包内容
look at Attachments.
查看附件
There they are.
就在这儿
Copy and Paste.
拷贝并粘贴
And I think this Travel Details
我认为这个 Travel Details
one is going to be particularly
会特别有用
helpful because it has that
因为它有麻烦的
troublesome Book button in it.
“Book” 按钮
Alright, now I'm ready to send
现在我准备将我的整个
my entire Xcode Localization
Xcode 本地化目录
Catalog off to my localizers.
发送给我的本地化人员
Now the great thing is they're
现在最棒的是
really fast and they're already
他们非常快 已经完成了
done.
所以我们可以继续
those translations.
导入这些翻译
Just going to go back to my
只要回到 我的项目
Make sure I have the project
确保我选择了该项目
And as before, go to Editor and
和以前一样
this time choose Import
转到编辑器
Localizations.
这次选择 Import Localizations
Okay? So I'm going to pick my
所以我要选择
Return to Xcode Localization
Return to Xcode Localization Catalog.
Click Open.
点按打开
And now I get a comparison view
现在我得到一个
the same as in Xcode 9 that
与 Xcode 9 相同的
shows me any warnings, errors,
对比视图
and changes regarding my
它显示了有关我的
strings.
字符串的所有警告 错误和更改
So here, it's just warning me I
所以在这里 这只是警告我
didn't get any translations for
我没有为 infoplist.strings
my infoplist.strings.
做任何翻译
But that's okay.
但没关系 我没有要求这些翻译
translations, so I'm just going
所以我就
to ignore this warning.
忽略这个警告
I can also check on what's
我也可以检查有什么变化
changing.
所以在这里
storyboard, we can see I'm
如果我们看故事板
getting real French translations
可以看到
to replace those copies of the
真正的法语翻译
English in the strings.
来替换字符串中的英文副本
So I'm just going to click
所以我只要点按导入 就像那样
And just like that, all of the
我的字符串和
translations for my strings and
非字符串资源
non-strings resources are in the
的所有翻译都在
right place in my project.
我的项目的正确位置
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Alright, so let's double check
好的 我们再检查一下
I'll just do spot check of a
我将对一些文件
couple files.
进行抽查
Okay, main.strings.
好的 main.strings
That looks like French to me.
看着是法语
I don't actually speak it.
其实我不会讲法语
Let's check the image.
检查一下图像
Yes, that's also in French.
也是法语
Okay, so let's run through the
好 让我们再用法语
app one more time in French and
运行一下这个 App
make sure everything looks good.
确保一切都没问题
So to do that, I'm going to
我要选择
select my Active Scheme, choose
活动模式（Active Scheme）
Edit Scheme.
再选择编辑模式（Edit Scheme）
Set the application language to
将 App 语言设置为法语
French and the application
将 App 国家或地区
region to France.
设置为法国
Now I'm ready to run.
现在我准备好运行了
We're going to stop the English
先停止英语运行
Okay? So in just a moment here,
稍等一小会儿
we should get our app entirely
我们应该可以得到
in French.
一个法语的 App
Okay, looks good so far.
好的到目前为止看起来不错
I'm just going to go through
我只需要快速浏览一下
that Book button.
这样我就可以查看 “Book” 按钮
Alright, Browse, let's go to
好的浏览一下
Mars again.
我们再回到火星
I really like Gale Creator.
我真的很喜欢 Gale Creator
Okay, great.
真棒
That Book button was translated
那个 “Book” 按钮翻译对了
correctly.
我把这部分的屏幕快照
that I included screenshot of
也包括进去 可能真的很有帮助
If we check on the dates here,
如果我们查看一下日期
alright, I did not have to send
我不需要给我的
a list of months to my
翻译们发送月份列表
Instead, I used this nice date
而是直接用
picker that in turn uses a
日期选择器
formatter and I got these
然后使用格式化程序
localizations for free.
就能免费获得这些本地化内容
And likewise, by using a
同样 通过使用格式化程序的
formatter for the price, I got
价格模板
the correct number formatting
可以得到正确的数字格式
and the price given in Euros.
和欧元价格
Alright, so that was super easy
所以无论是字符串
to get my strings and non-string
还是非字符串
resources all in French as
这都是一种简易转换为法语的方法
easily as I would've done with
就像我只用
just the string resources in
Xcode 9 中的
Xcode 9.
字符串资源一样
So with that, let's go back to
最后 让我们
the slides and wrap up our
回到幻灯片
discussion of Xcode Localization
结束对 Xcode 本地化目录的讨论
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Alright, so we have introduced
好的我们已经介绍了
the Xcode Localization Catalog
Xcode 本地化目录作为
as Xcode's new standard for
Xcode 的新的本地化
localization export and import.
导出和导入标准
It provides more flexibility for
为你的翻译人员
your translators and allows you
提供了更多的灵活性
to conveniently provide more
并允许你方便地提供
visual and functional context to
更多的视觉和功能背景
better help them generate
以更好地帮助他们
high-quality translations the
第一次就做出
first time.
高质量的翻译
It has increased file type
它增加了文件类型支持
support, so you can export and
因此你可以像使用基于
import your non-string resources
字符串的资源那样
as easily as you've been doing
轻松地导出和导入
with your string based
非字符串资源
We've also updated Xcode build
我们还更新了 Xcode 构建版本
to use the Xcode Localization
以使用 Xcode 本地化目录
Catalog for continuous
提供持续支持
And if you have content out for
如果你现在有
localization right now, don't
本地化的内容
worry, you can still import
不要担心
those XLIFFs when they come back
当 Xcode 和 Xcode 构建
to you both Xcode and Xcode
都向后兼容时
Build are backwards compatible.
你仍然可以导入这些 XLIFFs 文件
Alright, so with that, I'm going
好了 现在我把场地交给 Chris
to hand it over to Chris to talk
他会和你们谈谈
to you about localizing intent
如何通过本地化目标
definition files for the
定义文件来
creation of Siri Shortcuts.
创建 Siri 捷径
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Vivian.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Vivian
Wow, that's really awesome.
这可真棒
I'm really looking forward to
我非常期待
that trip to Mars.
此次的火星之旅
So I'm going to be showing you
我将向你们展示如何
how to localize Siri Shortcuts
通过本地化你的目标
by localizing your intent
定义来本地化 Siri 捷径
And your intent definitions are
你的目标定义是
created in intent definition
在 Xcode 中的
files in Xcode.
目标定义文件中创建的
And these are what you use to
这些都是你用来
define your custom intents for
为 Siri 捷径
Siri Shortcuts.
定义的自定义目标
They're just files with an
它们只是具有目标定义
intent definition extension that
扩展名的文件
have a custom editor in Xcode.
在 Xcode 中具有自定义编辑器
And we've designed them to take
我们设计它们是为了
advantage of base localization
利用基础本地化
so when you go to translate your
所以当你翻译你的目标时
intents, you don't have a bunch
你没有很多不同的
of different intent definition
目标定义文件
files, one per language, you
每种语言一个
just use strings files to
你只需要使用字符串文件
localize the strings that are in
来本地化你的
your intent definitions.
目标定义中的字符串
And, of course, we also support
当然 我们也支持
stringsdict files for a variety
stringsdict 文件
of cases like pluralization
用于各种情况
rules and variable-width
如复数规则和
strings.
可变宽度字符串
And if you haven't yet, I
如果你还没看过
strongly encourage you to check
我强烈建议你
out the Introduction to Siri
去看看昨天大会的
Shortcuts Session that happened
Siri 捷径的介绍
yesterday and that's available
它可以用于流媒体
Now let's take a quick walk
现在让我们
through the Intent Definition
快速浏览一下 目标定义编辑器
Here we have an intent
这里我们有一个
definition for our Vacation
度假星球 App 的
Planet application and we have
目标定义
an intent for booking a
我们有一个
vacation.
预定度假的目标
Of course, one of the things
当然 你想在你的目标中
that you'll want to localize in
本地化的
your intent is the title and the
内容有标题和
description of the intent
目标本身的描述
But most of what you're going to
但是大部分你将要
be localizing for your intent
为你的目标定义
definition are the shortcut
本地化的
types that are composed together
是从目标参数组成的
from the intents parameters.
快捷类型
And of course, when an intent is
当然 当一个目标被调用时
invoked, it produces a response
它也会产生一个响应
as well and these can also be
这些响应也可以通过
customized with Response
响应模板进行定制
Templates and these Response
这些响应模板的
Templates are localized in
本地化方式与
exactly the same way as your
你的快捷方式
shortcut types.
类型完全相同
Now let's take a deeper look at
现在让我们更深入地
the actual structure of an
了解一个目标的实际结构
intent and what's localizable
以及它内部的
within it.
可本地化结构
An intent is really a collection
目标实际上是
of parameters that have a
具有各种类型的
variety of types.
参数的集合
So they can have types like
它们可以有整数
integer or string and you saw
或昨天你们看到的字符串类型
yesterday that they also support
它们也支持
custom objects and they support
自定义对象
enumerations that are defined
它们支持在目标定义中
right in your intent definition.
定义的枚举类型
And these parameters are
这些参数被组合成
combined together into different
不同的快捷方式
shortcut types that have a nice
有一个可读性很强的标题
And of course, responses are
当然 响应也是属性的集合
also collections of properties
这些属性具有
that have well understood types
容易理解的类型
again like string or integer and
比如字符串或整数
can also have types from your
还可以具有
enumerations.
枚举类型
And when you go to localize your
当你本地化
intent definition, the things
你的目标定义时
that you're going to be
最需要本地化的是你的快捷方式
shortcut types and your response
类型和响应模板
And for the most part, what
主要来说
we're going to talk about today
我们今天要讨论的是
is how to localize your shortcut
如何本地化你的
types because you localize your
快捷方式类型
response templates in exactly
因为本地化相应模板的方式
the same way.
完全相同
So here's an example from our
所以这里是我们的
Vacation Planet app.
度假星球 App 的一个例子
This is the shortcut type for
这是预订旅行的快捷方式
booking a trip and that type of
这种类型的旅行
trip there is actually a
实际上有一个
placeholder for one of our
占位符用于枚举
This enumeration lets you book a
此枚举允许你
flight or it lets you book a
预订航班或
cruise, or it lets you book a
预订邮轮
vacation package.
或者预定假期
And when Xcode goes to localize
当 Xcode 本地化
your intent definition file,
你的目标定义文件时
when you press that localize
当你按下 Vivian 给你的
button that Vivian showed you,
本地化按钮时
what's going to happen is Xcode
Xcode 会为这个
will produce one each of its
枚举中的部分
strings for the members of that
生成一个字符串
And that happens to work because
因为我们选择了
of the particular words we
特定的词
chose.
所以它恰好起作用
Because our template says "Book
因为我们的模板上
a flight" and uses that
写着 “预订航班”
indefinite article, we can or
使用不定冠词
"Book a type" and uses that
我们可以
indefinite article, we can book
或 “预订一种类型”
a flight, book a cruise, or book
使用不定冠词
a vacation package because they
我们可以预订航班 预订邮轮 或预订度假套餐
all start with consonants
因为他们都以辅音开头
because that's the rule in
因为这是英语的规则
But what happens if I add a new
但是如果我为我的
value to my enumeration to
列举增加了一个
represent booking an expedition,
新的值来代表预定一次探险 比如说火星
Well, Xcode is just going to
Xcode 只是在它的
generate in its strings file
字符串文件中生成
"Book a expedition" which isn't
"Book a expedition"
really very grammatical.
这实际上不是很合乎语法
Fortunately, though, these
幸运的是
strings files are keyed by
这些字符串文件是
well-defined IDs and stable IDs
由明确定义的 ID 和稳定 ID 来控制的
so you can just go into the
因此你可以直接进入字符串文件
strings file and change it so
并对其进行更改
that it's properly grammatical.
以使其符合语法
Now English isn't the only
英语并不是唯一
language that has this kind of
一种具有这种语法
grammatical agreement.
一致性的语言
Different languages, of course,
当然不同的语言
have different grammatical
有不同的
agreement.
语法一致性
So you'll need to do the same
法语的话 你需要做
kind of thing say in French,
同样的事
where you'll need to make the
你需要让冠词的词性
gender of the article agree with
和它所指的
the gender of the noun that it's
名词的词性一致
Now let's take a quick look at a
现在让我们快速
more complex example.
看一个更复杂的例子
Here we have a shortcut type for
这里有一个快捷方式
number of people and once again,
用于为一些人
when generating that strings
预订假期
file, Xcode, well, it's going to
同样 在生成字符串
combine together the template
文件 Xcode 时
with the values from the
它会将模板与
enumeration.
枚举值组合在一起
However, it's not going to
但是 它不会为
generate one string for every
每个可能的整数
possible integer as well.
生成一个字符串
Instead, it's going to leave the
相反 它会在
strings that it generates with a
字符串中
placeholder in them that the
保留一个占位符
shortcut system will replace at
由快捷方式系统在运行时替换
And once again, this looks like
再说一遍 这看起来
it should be reasonable.
应该是合理的
Right? it says, you know, book a
对吧 上面写着
vacation or book a flight for
为一些人订一个假期
some number of people.
或者订一个航班
And in our strings file, we get
在我们的字符串文件中
that generated ID and that
我们得到了生成的 ID 和字符串
string that says, oh, book a
上面写的是
cruise for some number of people
为一些人预订一次巡航
with that placeholder still in
这个占位符仍然在那里
there; however, when I go to
然而当我为自己去
book a cruise for just myself to
预订一艘游轮去庆祝
celebrate a great WWDC, what's
伟大的 WWDC 时
going to be shown as an actual
真正的快捷方式是
shortcut is the string "Book a
“预订一个人的游轮”
cruise for 1 people" which isn't
这句英语
grammatical English.
在语法上不合规范
However, these support
但是 这些文件
stringsdict files as well so you
也支持字符串词典（stringsdict）文件
can do all of the pluralization
因此你可以做
that you need and have the
所有你需要的多元化
system take care of it for you.
并让系统为你处理它
Here in the stringsdict file, we
在字符串词典（stringsdict）文件中
have the dictionary itself keyed
我们有字典本身
by that string that I showed you
由我在字符串文件中
from the strings file.
展示的那个字符串进行键控
You can either use that or you
你可以使用它
can use the ID as the key.
也可以使用 ID 作为关键
And then we've produced another
然后我们又生成了
string that is what is actually
另一个字符串
going to be shown in the user
它实际上会在用户界面中显示出来
And here, we're referring to
在这里 我们指的是
another variable which can then
另一个变量它可以
be substituted for either the
根据英语的复数规则
one or other cases based on
来代替此变量
English's pluralization rules.
或另一个变量
And to learn more about
要了解关于
stringsdict files, you should
stringsdict 文件的
see our session from last year
更多信息
Localizing with Xcode 9 that's
可以查看我们的分会
available in the WWDC
从去年开始 在 WWDC App 中
application.
使用 Xcode 9 进行本地化
Here, if I go to book my cruise
如果我现在去
now, this operating system will
预订我的邮轮
say, oh, I'm booking for one
这个操作系统会说
person, so let's use the case
哦 我为一个人进行预订
for one and I get a properly
所以我们用一个人的情况
grammatical phrase.
得到一个恰当的语法短语
And similarly, if I want to book
同样的 如果我想为
a cruise for all of us, you
我们所有人预订一次邮轮之旅
know, after all I'm not the only
你知道 毕竟我不是
one up here, the system will say
这里唯一的一个
"Book a cruise for 3 people."
系统会说 “为三个人预订一次邮轮之旅”
Now let's talk about intents
现在我们来聊聊
that are created in code.
在代码中创建的目标
If you're creating an intent in
如果你正在代码中
code to donate it to the system,
创建一个目标来
that isn't necessarily the point
将其捐赠给系统
at which a shortcut will be
那么这并不一定是显示快捷方式的地方
That can be displayed far off at
在将来的某个时刻
some point in the future based
可以根据用户的操作
on the user's actions.
显示这些内容
So we have a new API that
我们有一个新的 API
creates a deferred localizable
来创建一个延迟的
string that will be localized at
可本地化字符串
the point where the string is
它将在字符串呈现给
presented to the user.
用户的地方进行本地化
And this is necessary because
这是必要的
donating an intent to the system
因为向系统提供目标
is really telling the system,
实际上是在告诉系统
hey, the user performed some
嘿 用户在我的 App 中
action in my application that
执行了一些操作
you might want to offer them
你可能会在
again at some other point.
其他时候再次提供它们
And, fortunately, this API is
幸运的是 这个 API
extremely simple to use.
非常容易使用
It's just one call added to NS
它只是一个添加到
String that you can use to wrap
nsstring 的调用
the string that you're going to
你可以使用它来包装
assign to that intent you
要分配给你在代码中
created in code.
创建的目标的字符串
So let's talk quickly about what
让我们快速讨论
we've seen.
一下我们所看到的
We've seen that Xcode combines
我们已经看到
your shortcut types with the
Xcode 将你的快捷方式类型
enumerations that you've defined
与在目标定义中
in your intent definition when
生成字符串文件时
it's generating the strings
定义的枚举组合在一起
files.
你可以使用字符串
stringsdict files to localize
和 stringsdict 文件
your shortcuts.
本地化你的快捷方式
And if you're creating an intent
如果你在代码中创建
in code to donate it to the
一个目标捐给系统
system, to inform the system of
通知用户操作的系统
a user action that might be
可能会重复
repeated, you can use deferred
你可以使用延迟局部目标字符串
Localized Intents String to wrap
结束字符串以这样一种方式
that string in such a way that
它将局部呈现
it'll be localized when it's
给用户的时候
presented to the user, not at
不是在你的
the point where it's created in
App 中创建的那个
So if the user changes their
因此 如果用户在捐赠
phone's language in between when
该目标的过程中
you've donated that intent, and
更改了手机的语言
when a shortcut is displayed, it
并且显示了快捷方式
still follows the user's phone
则仍然会遵循用户的手机语言
Now when you define strings in a
现在 当你在
stringsdict file, they are
stringsdict 文件中定义字符串时
actually going to be preferred
它们实际上在运行时会被优先选择
That means you can do the
这意味着你可以在
majority of your localization in
所有不需要复数规则
your strings files for all of
的情况下
the cases where you don't need
在你的字符串文件中
things like plural agreement and
执行大部分本地化操作
then you can just provide a
然后你可以提供一个
strings file or a stringsdict
字符串文件或
file with the same name as your
与你的目标定义名称
intent definition as an
相同的字符串文件来覆盖
And when you create that
当你创建
stringsdict file, you can use
stringsdict 文件时
either the strings themselves or
你可以使用字符串本身
the strings IDs that Xcode
或者字符串 ID
assigns as keys in your strings
Xcode 在你的字符串文件中
file as the Localized String Key
指定为键
and string somewhat measure of
作为本地化的
stability in case you actually
字符串键和字符串
decide to change things in your
在某种程度上
intent definition.
你决定在你的目标定义中做些改变
So now, I'd like to bring Vivian
现在请回 Vivian
back up to show you exactly how
来告诉大家
to do this, how this whole
我们该如何操作
process works in Xcode.
这整个过程是如何在 Xcode 中工作的
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Chris.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Chris
Alright, so once you go to Mars
一旦你去了一次火星
once, you're probably going to
你可能会想
want to go again and again and
去第二次 第三次
again because those trips are
因为这些旅行真的很便宜
really cheap, as we saw.
就像我们看到的那样
And it would be nice if our app
如果我们的 App 能给
could suggest additional trips
这些频繁旅行的人
to these frequent fliers and
作出额外的旅行建议
give them a shortcut to book the
并提供下一次假期的快捷方式 那就太棒了
So with that in mind, I've added
考虑到这一点
an intent definition to our
我为我们的项目添加了一个目标定义
Let's go look at it.
我们来看一下
Okay, here's our intent
这是我们的目标定义
So we have a custom intent
有一个定制的目标
called "Book Item," has a title,
叫做 “Book Item”
a description, and down here is
有标题 有描述
the actual suggestion.
下面是实际的建议
So it is book a type for
所以它是旅行者的
travelers, people.
一种类型
Like Chris said, it's a
就像 Chris 说的那样
combination of parameters.
这是参数的组合
So we can see travelers is an
所以我们可以看到
integer and type is defined in
旅行者是一个整数
this enum here, so we can see it
类型是在这里的
can be a flight, a cruise, a
enum 中定义的
vacation package, or an
所以我们可以看到它可以是一次飞行
expedition.
一次巡航 一个整套假期 或者一次探险
Now if our user follows through
现在 如果我们的用户
with a suggestion and books
继续提供建议并
another trip, we need to give
预订另一次旅行
them some kind of feedback.
我们需要给他们一些反馈
So for that we have a response
因此我们有一个回应
and there's just a success or a
关于我们是否可以
failure message as to whether we
预订他们的旅行
could book their trip.
只有成功或失败的信息
And this is likewise a
这同样是
combination of parameters.
参数的组合
Now, of course, since we have
当然 既然我们有面向
user facing strings, we need to
用户的字符串
localize them.
我们需要对它们进行本地化
So let's do that.
现在就开始吧
Just like I did for the image, I
就像我对图像所做的一样
just go to the right here, click
我只要到这里 点按本地化
Now intent definition files are
现在目标定义文件
going to be like interface
将会像界面构建版本（interface builder）
builder files where we have one
文件一样 我们在 strings 文件中有一个
intent definition and all of our
目标定义和
translations in strings files.
所有的翻译
So I want to put it in base.
我想把它放在底部
Click Localize.
点按本地化
Okay. And I want to check
好的 我想看一下法语
Okay, so at this point, Xcode
在这一点上
has created a strings file for
Xcode 为法语翻译
the French translations to be
创建了一个字符串文件
And here we go.
就在这儿
Alright, and you can see as I
好的 大家可以看到
scroll through, it has every
当我滚动的时候
possible string given the
它有所有可能的字符串
possible values for the
给定在枚举中定义的
parameters defined in enums.
参数的可能值
This is great because, again, I
这很好 因为我
don't speak French but I know
不会说法语
from the slides that flight and
但我从幻灯片上知道
cruise have different
航班和邮轮有
grammatical gender, they're
不同的词性
going to need different forms of
它们需要
the word for "a."
不同形式的冠词
Alright, but there's still some
但我还是可以
grammar problems I can fix and
解决一些语法问题的
those are the ones in English,
这些是英文的
the case of one person and an
一个人和一个
expedition.
探险队的例子
So to do that, I need, or at
为此 我需要 或者说
least to fix the plural case,
至少要修正复数情况
I'm going to add a stringsdict
我要添加一个和
file with the same name as my
目标定义同名的
intent definition.
stringsdict 文件
So just go over here to my
到我的项目这里
Create new file.
创建新文件
And I'm going to use the
我将使用 Xcode 9 中
stringsdict template that was
添加的 stringsdict 模板
Click Next.
点按下一步（Next）
Alright, here's the important
好的 这是非常重要的部分
part.
我要确保我的名字准确无误
Intents. Okay.
目标 好的
Create. Now I don't need to go
创建 现在我不需要
into my French strings file to
进入我的法语字符串文件
find the ID for my intent.
来找到我的目标的 ID
I can actually go into the
我可以进入
intent definition file because
目标定义文件
these are required to be unique.
因为它们是唯一的
I can actually copy directly
我可以直接从这里拷贝
from here, alright, copy, and go
拷贝 然后粘贴
my stringsdict, and paste.
然后回到 stringsdict
Alright, you can see here Xcode
好的 你可以在这里看到
actually formatted the
Xcode 在粘贴时为我格式化了参数
parameters for me when I pasted
这已经为 Siri 捷径
for Siri Shortcuts.
做好了准备
Okay, so at this point, I'm
好了 现在我准备好
ready to fill in the rest of my
要填我的
plural dictionary.
复数字典了
I'm only going to need one and
我只需要一个和另一个
other because I'm doing English.
因为我用的是英语
So I have singular and plural.
所以我有单数和复数
But like any good cooking show,
但是就像任何一个好的烹饪节目一样
I have the finished file ready.
我已经准备好了完成的文件
So I'm going to swap that in.
我把它换进去
Alright, say goodbye to this
好的 跟它说再见吧
guy.
我们去找
one.
最后一个 好了
Yes, Xcode, I want to make a
是的 Xcode
copy.
我想拷贝一份 好了
Alright, let's look at it.
好的 我们来看一下
So we're going to look at a case
我们来看一个同时
where I fixed two problems at
解决两个问题的例子
So if we check Book Expedition,
如果我们查一下 “Book Expedition”
the string here is "Book a
这里的字符串是
expedition" but then in the
“Book a Expedition”
plural dictionary, I have the
但在复数字典里
case of one person or any other
我这里有一个人
number of people.
或其他人数的人
What I also did here was fix
我在这里所做的
that a/an situation so the
是修正了不定冠词的适用情况
string is actually displayed
所以字符串实际显示
we'll use an.
我们将使用 an
Okay. So I have the finished
好的 所以我有我的手机上
version of the app running on my
运行的 App 的完成版本
phone.
我们通过它
check the shortcut that's
来检查创建的快捷方式
Alright, I'm just going to go to
我只想和以前一样
the same place as before.
去那个地方
I really like Gale Creator.
我真的很喜欢 Gale Creator
Okay, Browse, Mars, Gale
浏览 火星 Gale Creator
Creator, and let's not go for a
我们不要只去一天
day.
我们要去 这就行了
Okay, this time I'm going to go
好的 这次我要独自一人去
by myself because I want to
因为我想
check the one case.
检查一下一个人的情况
There. When I tap Book, that
好了 当我点按 “Book” 时
actually created the shortcut
实际上创建了快捷方式
and donated it.
并捐赠了它
So now we can go look at it.
所以现在我们可以去看看它
you can find these under
可以通过
Settings, Siri &amp; Search.
设置 Siri 搜索来找到
There. Book an expedition for
就这样 预订一场
one person.
一个人的冒险
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Alright, so this is great for
好的 这对英语来说很好 我修好了它
but I'm still going to need to
但我仍然需要将其
localize this into French.
本地化为法语
And the great thing is, it's
最重要的是
just as easy as the first demo.
它与第一个演示一样简单
So we can go back to Xcode.
所以我们可以回到 Xcode
Alright. I'm going to make sure
好的 我要确保我将我的
I localize my stringsdict
字符串词本地化
because I didn't do that yet.
因为我还没有这样做
English, yes.
英语 是的
Check French.
检查法语
Otherwise, it won't be exported.
否则它不会被导出
Okay, so now I just select my
好的 现在我只需
project again.
再次选择我的项目
Go to Editor.
去编辑器
Export for Localization.
导出为本地化
I'm going to call this vacation
我打算称这个
plan loc2 since it's the second
假期计划为 loc2
round of localization.
因为它是第二轮本地化
Double check, yes, I'm doing
仔细检查 是的
French again.
我选择的还是法语 点按保存
And now Xcode creates another
现在 Xcode 创建另一个
Xcode Localization Catalog.
Xcode 本地化目录
So if we go look at it,
我们来看看它
okay, let's check localized
检查一下本地化的内容
If we look at the XLIFF, you can
如果我们看一下 XLIFF
see here highlighted in red are
可以看到红色突出显示的
all the new strings from the
是目标定义中的
intent definition but we also
所有新字符串
have all the translations I
但我们也有第一次
imported the first time.
导入的所有翻译
So you can have an incremental
所以你可以有一个
localization process where you
增量本地化的过程
develop your apps sum, you get
在这个过程中
that version localized, you make
你开发好了 App
some tweaks for version two, and
获得本地化版本
you don't lose anything when you
然后对版本 2 进行了一些调整
export for another round of
当你输出另一轮本地化时
localization.
不会丢失任何东西
And this works for the
这也适用于
non-string resources as well.
非字符串资源
So this will have the French
这里有我的图像的
version of my image.
法语版本
Great. So I can develop my app,
棒极了 所以我可以开发我的 App
keep localizing, keep working
继续本地化 继续工作
and it's all just as easy as the
这一切都像第一次一样简单
first time and it covers both my
它涵盖了我的字符串
strings and my non-string
我的非字符串资源
resources and my intent
和我的目标定义
definitions so that I can
以便我可以
suggest additional trips to
建议其它的火星旅行
Alright, so with that, I'm going
好的我们重新交给
to turn it back over to Chris
Chris 由他来进行
for the last time to summarize.
最终的总结
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you again, Vivian.
&gt;&gt; 再次谢谢你 Vivian
Wow, that's really great.
这可真棒
I'm really looking forward to
我真的很期待这些旅行
So as you've seen, Xcode
正如你所看到的
Localization Catalogs are our
Xcode 本地化目录
new standard in Xcode for
是我们用于本地化的
localization.
Xcode 的新标准
And these support all of the
这些支持你项目中的
localizable resources in your
所有可本地化资源
project, not just the strings
而不仅仅是基于
based resources.
字符串的资源
And they also provide
而且更为灵活
flexibility to provide context
可以为本地化人员
to localizers, whether that's
提供上下文
putting in screenshots from your
无论是从测试中
tests or putting in readme files
放入屏幕快照还是
or movies of the use of your
放入自述文件或
application, you can give your
如何使用 App 的电影
localizers the context that they
都可以为本地化人员提供
need to ensure you get exactly
所需的上下文以确保
the right translations the first
第一次翻译就可以达到相应的准确率
And you've also seen that Siri
你也看到 Siri 捷径
Shortcuts are easy to localize
很容易通过本地化
by localizing your intent
你的目标定义文件
definition files, that these use
进行本地化
base localization with strings
这些文件使用字符串文件
files and that you can use
进行基本本地化
stringsdict files where
并且你可以在适当的地方
appropriate to handle things
使用 stringsdict 文件来处理
like pluralization rules in a
各种语言的
variety of languages, and that
复数规则
when you're creating an intent
当你创建代码捐赠目标时
to donate in code, you can use
可以使用延迟
deferred localized intent
本地化目标字符串
strings to ensure that a
以确保从捐赠目标
shortcut that's created from
创建的快捷方式
that donated intent is localized
在向用户显示时
at the time that it's displayed
进行本地化
to the user, rather than at the
而不是在你
point where you donated it.
捐赠它的时候
For more information, you can
若要了解更多信息
see our session page on the WWDC
请访问在 WWDC 网站
website.
可以看到我们的会议页面
Thank you again so much for
感谢大家能够参与 WWDC
coming and I hope you continue
希望大家可以
to have a great WWDC.
好好享受此次盛会
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]